Guide to the Morris State Bank (Pony, Montana) Records 1899-1927
Montana Historical Society Archives
- Morris State Bank
  - General Correspondence
    - Madison County government (includes R.N. Hawkins, E.M. Smith, H.C. Vinson, Phebe Comfort-Williams), 1910-1916 (Box-folder 4 / 30)
    - McCaull-Dinsmore Company, 1912-1917 (Box-folder 4 / 31)
    - Samuel A. Mendenhall; Leah Morris Mendenhall, 1910-1917 (Box-folder 4 / 32)
    - Montana Bankers Association, 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
    - Montana State Examiner, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
    - Montana Treasurer's Office, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
    - Montana state government (includes Agricultural Experiment Station, Attorney General, Dept. of Banking, Dept. of Public Instruction, Governor, Secretary of State, State Dairy Commission, State Grain Inspection Dept., State Mine Inspector's Office), 1910-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
    - Montana companies and organizations (includes Montana Central Elevator Company, Montana Electric Company, Montana Exposition Commission, Montana Farmers' Institutes, Montana Life Insurance Company, Montana Power Company, Montana-Tonopah Mining Company), 1910-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
    - Charles E. Morris, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
    - M (correspondents include W.A. Mack, Madison County Publicity Club, Madison State Bank, J.C. Mahony [re P.J. Leonard Estate], W.D. Manley, Mammoth Mining and Power Company, Charles A. Marriner, L.E. Marshall, Frank E. Martin, Seward Mason, Charles Mattison, Julian May, F.E. McCann, A.J. McCormick, H.W. McDaniel, J.F. McDonnell, McLeod Lumber Company, Mrs. C.V. McVey, William Melzer, Mary L. Miller, William M. Moon, Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company, Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
    - National Bank of Commerce in New York, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
    - National Life Insurance Company of Montana, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
    - Norris Mercantile Company, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Company, 1912-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 11)
    - N-O (correspondents include National Bank of Montana, National Surety Company, Franz Nollaeger, Alex Norris, John Northey, Northwestern Electric Lamp Company, Northwestern National Bank, Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corporation, L.B. Olds, John Osterman), 1910-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 12)
    - Ole Peterson, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
    - P (correspondents include Pacific Tank and Pipe Company, L.R. Packard, H.A. Paddock, N.D. Parks, Passmore and Company, J.H. Patrick, William Pearce, Mrs. B.M. Phillips, H.S. Phillips, J.M. Pile, Town of Pony, George Powell, Jonathan W. Powell, G.R. Powers, John E. Price), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 14)
    - T.E. Richardson, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 15)
    - R (correspondents include George L. Ramsey, J.C. Ramsey, Ranchers Hail and Fire Insurance Company, T.D. Randall and Company, H.H. Randolph and Company, John Rasmussen, W.A. Reel, Leonardo Remington, F.C. Richtmyer, J.G. Roberts, L.W. Roper, William Routzahn, George A. Rundell, Glenn M. Rundell), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 16)
    - Sears and Dawes, 1916 (Box-folder 5 / 17)
    - C.S. Shoemaker, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 5 / 18)
    - Z.A. Short, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 5 / 19)
    - S (correspondents include George W. Sanford, Lester Sanford, H.H. Sappington, Edward Scharnikow, J.P. Schlichtig [?], John Schuten, Security State Bank of Havre, Robert A. Semple, Shaw and Borden Company, Arthur Shaw, Loren Shaw, Harriet Shenk, Frank T. Sheppard, Sheridan State Bank, Kate Shields, J.C. Shirley, George L. Shuman and Company, Silver Bow National Bank, E.M. Smith, Harry Smith, Isaac Snodderly, Fred Snowball, E.H. Sparrell, Spaulding Manufacturing Company, State Bank of Somers, Anna W. Stewart, John W. Stiver, Fred H. Stock, A.H. Stoddard, John H. Stoker), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 20)
    - Tinsley family (includes Bazel Tinsley, Enoch W. Tinsley, W.E. Tinsley), 1910-1914 (Box-folder 5 / 21)
    - T (correspondents include Walter Talland; J.L. Templeman; H.R. Thixton; A.P. Thomas; Thompson, Towle and Company; Thompson Falls Power Company; Toberman, Mackey and Company; Tootle-Campbell Dry Goods Company; F.N. Truesdale; C.E. Tuke), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 22)
    - Union Bank and Trust Company (includes George L. Ramsey, Frank Bogart, S. McKennan), 1910-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 23)
    - United States government (includes Assay Office, Bureau of the Census, Food Administration, Geological Survey, Interstate Commerce Commission, Postal Savings System, Treasury Dept.), 1912-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 24)
    - U-V (correspondents include Union Investment Company, United Drug Company, United States Fidelity and Guaranty Company, United States Smelting Company, L.W. VanAkin, Van Dusen Harrington Company), 1910-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 25)
    - William K. Weaver, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 5 / 26)
    - Wells and Dickey Company, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 5 / 27)
    - H.F. West, Undertaker (includes Davis and West), 1913-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 28)
    - Ed E. Williams, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 5 / 29)
    - W-Z (correspondents include Franz Wallaeger, Thomas J. Walsh, I.S. Ware, Washoe Sampler, David Watson, W.F. Watt, Fritz Wehrbein, I.A. Westmoreland, Henry Wetmore, George W. White, White and Son, Whitehall State Bank, Lamie Wickham, J. Wicklund, W.F. Widner, R.H. Wiedman, James Wilkie, O.W. Wilkins, Willow Creek State Bank, R.G. Wilson, Woodrow Wilson, J.W. Winning, Francis C. Wood, W.A. Wood, R. Lee Word, E.W. Wullenwaber, Valentino Zanella, unidentified), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 5 / 30)
  - Court Papers
    - Miscellaneous (includes garnishments, subpoenas, etc.), 1907-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 31)
  - Financial Records
    - Assessments for state examiner's fund, state depository interest fund, and state banking fund, 1903-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 32)
    - Bills, receipts, etc. [sampled], 1902-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 33)
    - Daily statement registers, Apr.1902- Jan.1912 (Volume Vol. 1-2)
    - Draft register, Apr.1902- Jan.1907 (Volume Vol. 3)
    - Individual bank accounts [scattered], 1904-1916 (Box-folder 5 / 34)
    - Journals, Apr.1902- Jan.1908 (Volume Vol. 4-5)
    - "Paper held by Morris State Bank, Pony, Montana" (re loans); description of legal documents etc. deposited as collateral for loans, 1903-1913 (Box-folder 5 / 35)
    - Promissory notes, 1903-1911 (Box-folder 5 / 36)
    - Reports of condition sent to Office of State Examiner, State Bank Examiner, and Public Service Commission, 1903-1914, n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 1)
    - Taxes [scattered], 1902-1914 (Box-folder 6 / 2)
    - Teller's daily balance, June 1907- May 1908 (Volume Vol. 6)
    - Transactions with Montana banks: A-W [sampled], 1902-1917 (Box-folder 6 / 3)
    - Transactions with out-of-state banks: B-W [sampled], 1902-1911 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreements, deeds, mortgages, etc. [mostly 3rd parties], 1903-1917 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
    - Business licenses, 1906-1918 (Box-folder 6 / 6)
    - Notices of protest of checks (insufficient funds), 1902-1910 (Box-folder 6 / 7)
  - Subject Files
    - Citizens' Telephone Company, 1908-1912 (Box-folder 6 / 8)
    - Elling and Morris, Proprietors of the Pony Electric Light Plant, 1908-1915 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
    - Indian Gold Mining Company, 1908, 1917 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - Miscellany
    - Advertisements [sampled], n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 11)
    - Assay reports, 1903-1909 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
    - Grain shipment receipts, 1908, 1912 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
    - Insurance policies on Morris State Bank and on Charles E. Morris (Box-folder 6 / 14)
    - Letterheads; blank forms; etc., n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 15)
    - Pledge lists for YMCA drive for "our boys in France"; and for advertising for Madison County, 1917, n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 16)
    - Storage account for bank records; office machine guarantees; commercial report for Town of Pony, 1908, n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 17)
- Morris and Flint, Insurance
  - General Correspondence
    - A-D (correspondents include Aetna Insurance Company, James Althouse, American Central Insurance Company, Frank Armstrong, Associated Underwriters, [unidentified barber shop], Board of Fire Underwriters of the Pacific, Butte Association of Local Fire Insurance Agents, Cardwell School District #16, Ethel Carlson, James S. Dawes, Drake-Ballard Company), 1907-1922 (Box-folder 6 / 18)
    - Fireman's Fund Insurance Company, 1904-1918 (Box-folder 6 / 19)
    - F-G (correspondents include J.H. Featherston, R.R. Finlay, Flint-Lynn Lumber Company), 1907-1919 (Box-folder 6 / 20)
    - Home Insurance Company, 1909-1927 (Box-folder 6 / 21)
    - H-J (correspondents include M.C. Hayden, James T. Jelks), 1909, n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 22)
    - Liverpool and London and Globe Insurance Company, 1906-1918 (Box-folder 6 / 23)
    - M-O (correspondents include J.A. McAllister, D.R. McLeod, Samuel A. Mendenhall, Montana Auto and Garage Company, Montana-Revenue Gold Mining Company, Norris Mercantile Company, Oregon Mortgage Company), 1906-1916 (Box-folder 6 / 24)
    - St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Company (includes Christensen and Goodwin, agents; also includes letter to earlier Pony insurance agent), 1899-1908 (Box-folder 6 / 25)
    - S-W (correspondents include Benn A. Scott, United Insurance Company, Hugh C. Wakefield, Nelson J. White, Homer Wilson, World's Largest Insurance Company, S.B. Wright), 1908-1926 (Box-folder 6 / 26)
  - Reports
    - Reports and prospecti on mining properties (includes Black Pine Mining Company, Dailey Group of Mining Claims, Leviathan Gold Mining Company, Rocky Mountain Exploration Company, Stockton Copper Mining Company [includes drawings]), 1887-1907, n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 27)
  - Miscellany
    - Insurance policies and applications: A-Y, unidentified, 1908-1918 (Box-folder 6 / 28)
    - Miscellaneous (includes brochures, Montana hail insurance rates), 1912-1927, n.d. (Box-folder 6 / 29)
- Fred G. Smith
  - General Correspondence
    - A-E (correspondents include Charlie E. Allen, J.D. Allen, C.F. Cameron, Crandall Publishing Company, Walter S. Dodge, Educational Supply Company, Elling Estates Company, Equitable Life Assurance Society), 1906-1912 (Box-folder 6 / 30)
    - J.T. Farrell, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 6 / 31)
    - F-H (correspondents include Fairview Oro Plata Mining Company, First National Bank of Miles City, James A. Flint, Foster's School of Healing, George W. Gideon, E.S. Gilliam, Gimbel Brothers, L.C. Gooch, Frank W. Haskins, J.K. Heslet, M.P. Hobart, H.H. Holloway, James B. How), 1907-1912 (Box-folder 6 / 32)
    - Inter-Mountain Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1906-1908 (Box-folder 6 / 33)
    - I-L (correspondents include International Correspondence Schools; Jones and Yergey; Keeler Brothers; Lincoln County National Bank, Shoshone, Idaho; Walter A. Lord), 1906-1911 (Box-folder 6 / 34)
    - Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York (Henry S. Waldron, Eugene C. Winburn), 1906-1912 (Box-folder 6 / 35)
    - M-N (correspondents include Madison State Bank, Massachusetts Bonding and Insurance Company, A.J. McCormick, Montana-Nevada Mining Company, Abigail Morris, Fred F. Morris, W.C. Morris, Mystic Toilers, New York School of Automobile Engineers), 1907-1913 (Box-folder 6 / 36)
    - Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corporation (Hood and Penney, agents), 1907-1912 (Box-folder 6 / 37)
    - O-W (correspondents include Owenhouse Hardware Company, Parisian Dye House, N.D. Parker, J.H. Powell, J.C. Ramsay, A. Ira Renick, O.Y. Schulenburg, Schuneman and Evans, A.J. Smith, Art Smith, Hugh Smith, Leroy W. Smith, Lewis A. Smith, J.S. Staats, Trade Periodical Company, Washington Mail Order Company, Frank W. Wodrich), 1907-1916 (Box-folder 6 / 38)
  - Financial Records
    - Bank statements, bills, receipts, etc., 1906-1916 (Box-folder 6 / 39)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract for sale of property, description of farm property for sale, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 6 / 40)